okay so hello everyone in this video we are going to start with our basic
structure of schema okay so like for the schema part what we actually going to
make is like it's a kind of like skeleton of our chat app model okay so a chat
app what it has it has username it has password it has some some fields okay so
we are going to construct all that feel like email username password and all
of those fields so it is going to present so first we are going to work with
our user model okay so in the model folder go and make this user model.js okay
so after this what we are going to do is we are going to use our Mongoose package
okay so import Mongoose from Mongoose and now what we are going to do is like we are
going to construct our schema so user schema equal to Mongoose dot schema I'm
going to explain like why we are making this a schema don't worry so
const use schema is called to Mongoose dot schema and after that we are going to
just use this email field here so email and since our chat app will have
this email field so in the login functionality as well we will have this like
email we have to fill the email password and all confirm password field so
all of these so it comes under the schema part okay so a required equals to
true and the value of the email must be true so for all the distinct users
will have different different user emails no two persons can have the
same email okay so for the user name also we are going to select like this
only so type a string the user name must be of type a string and then a
required value will be true so since this would be required so we are going to
mark this is true and now after this first in the like when we are logging to
the chat application we will get this email field so we are going to fill the
email field after that we are going to fill our user name then after that what
will be the field so password field okay so password so the password will be
of type a string only so string and then after this required would
be true okay so required would be true and let's assume the minimum length for
any password would be something like six we can take six I think six would be
fine and then after that will have this one more like profile picture so
profile picture of a person so profile pick so type is a string and then
default value would be so let's suppose we are going to take some normal
value like let's take this one okay so normal Dp display picture
suppose okay so display picture for chat app okay so suppose we are going to
take this one and copy link address and we are going to use this default image
I'm going to change that okay so no issues and after this we will have this
time stamps here which will be true so whatever the time a new profile was
created at so for those kind of things we are going to use this is time stamps okay so
created at updated at so for all of these we are going to just use that sorry
not here actually here time stamps so it is going to take the time at which
the things are created at so time stamps equal to true and what we are going to
do is like export this one so export default this Mongo schema so export default
Mongo's dot model and let's name this as a user okay so user so user schema
okay so now we have worked on this user model so the next one would be
working on some other model okay